Guide to the Oregonian photographs collection circa 1850-1984
Oregon Historical Society, Research Library
- Washington State, 1889-1984; Series D
  - Maryhill (1) (Box-folder 75/10)
    Mostly photographs of the Maryhill Museum, but images of a nearby church and the war monument also included.
  - Maryhill (2) (Box-folder 75/11)
  - Mason City (Box-folder 75/12)
  - McGowan (Box-folder 75/13)
  - Merwin Hydroelectric Plant (Box-folder 75/14)
  - Miss Washington (Box-folder 75/15)
  - Moses Lake (Box-folder 75/16)
  - Moulton Falls (Box-folder 75/17)
  - North Beach (Box-folder 75/18)
  - North Bonneville (Box-folder 75/19)
  - North Head Lighthouse (Box-folder 75/20)
  - Northwest Electric Plant (Box-folder 75/21)
    Located on White Salmon River.
  - Mt. Olympus (Box-folder 75/22)
  - Pasco (Box-folder 75/23)
  - Pullman - Washington State University (Box-folder 75/24)
  - Mt. Rainier (Box-folder 75/25)
    Includes photographs of Mt. Rainier National Park.
  - Rock Island Hydroelectric Plant (Box-folder 75/26)
  - Mt. Saint Helens (Box-folder 75/27)
    Includes images from both before and after the May 1980 eruption.
  - Mt. St. Helens Eruption, 1980 (Box-folder 76/1)
    Includes photographs related to pre-eruptions in April 1980 and photographs related to the eruption's aftermath.
  - San Juan Islands (Box-folder 76/2)
    Contains two images related to monuments and structures related to the Pig War.
  - Seattle (Box-folder 76/3)
  - Seattle - Alaska-Yukon Pacific Exposition, 1908-1909 (Box-folder 76/4)
  - Seattle - University of Washington, 1911; 1918 (Box-folder 76/5)
  - Shelton (Box-folder 76/6)
  - Skamokawa (Box-folder 76/7)
  - State Inauguration (Box-folder 76/8)
    Photographs of two documents from 1889 regarding the the state's admission to the union.
  - Table Mountain (Box-folder 76/9)
    Includes a view of both Table Mountain and Oregon's Munra Point
  - Tacoma (Box-folder 76/10)
  - Trout Lake Ice Cave (Box-folder 76/11)
  - Vancouver, Subseries 1
    - General (Box-folder 76/12)
    - Aluminum Company of America (Alcoa) (Box-folder 76/13)
    - Carborundum Co. (Box-folder 76/14)
    - Centennial Celebration, 1925 August 17 (Box-folder 76/15)
    - Fort Vancouver (1) (Box-folder 76/16)
    - Fort Vancouver (2) (Box-folder 76/17)
    - Hospitals (Box-folder 76/18)
    - Hudson House (Box-folder 76/19)
  - Walla Walla (Box-folder 76/20)
  - Wenatchee (Box-folder 76/21)
  - White Salmon (Box-folder 76/22)
- Other US Locations, 1897-1979; Series E
  - Alaska (1) (Box-folder 77/1)
  - Alaska (2) (Box-folder 77/2)
  - Alaska (3) (Box-folder 77/3)
  - Alaska - Earthquakes, 1964 (Box-folder 77/4)
  - Arizona (Box-folder 77/5)
  - Arizona - Grand Canyon (Box-folder 77/6)
  - California, Subseries 1
    - General (1) (Box-folder 77/7)
    - General (2) (Box-folder 77/8)
    - Alcatraz Island (Box-folder 77/9)
    - Bay Area Rapid Transit (BART) (Box-folder 77/10)
    - Death Valley (Box-folder 77/11)
    - Disneyland (1) (Box-folder 77/12)
    - Disneyland (2) (Box-folder 77/13)
    - Earthquakes (Box-folder 77/14)
    - Mt. Lassen (Box-folder 78/1)
    - Los Angeles (Box-folder 78/2)
    - San Francisco (Box-folder 78/3)
      Includes images of the Bay Bridge and the Golden Gate Bridge.
    - San Francisco - Golden Gate International Exposition, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 78/4)
    - San Francisco - Panama-Pacific International Exposition, 1915 (Box-folder 78/5)
    - Mt. Shasta (Box-folder 78/6)
    - Lake Tahoe (Box-folder 78/7)
  - Colorado (Box-folder 78/8)
  - Georgia - Warm Springs (Box-folder 78/9)
  - Guam (Box-folder 78/10)
  - Hawaii (Box-folder 78/11)
  - Idaho (1) (Box-folder 78/12)
  - Idaho (2) (Box-folder 78/13)
  - Idaho - Brownlee Dam (Box-folder 78/14)
  - Idaho - Teton Dam Collapse, 1976 (Box-folder 78/15)
  - Illinois (Box-folder 78/16)
    Contains two images of houses in which Abraham Lincoln resided, and a photo of a crowd awaiting President Harding's funeral train near Chicago.
  - Minnesota (Box-folder 78/17)
  - Montana (Box-folder 78/18)
  - Montana - Glacier National Park (Box-folder 78/19)
  - Montana - Hebgen Lake Earthquake, 1959 (Box-folder 78/20)
  - Nevada (Box-folder 79/1)
  - Nevada - Hoover Dam (Box-folder 79/2)
    Includes photographs of officials involved with dam's construction.
  - New York - New York City (Box-folder 79/3)
    Includes a 1930 photograph of Grants Pass Cavemen parading in New York City.
  - New Hampshire (Box-folder 79/4)
  - Okalahoma (Box-folder 79/5)
  - South Dakota - Mt. Rushmore (Box-folder 79/6)
  - Texas - Dallas (Box-folder 79/7)
  - Utah (Box-folder 79/8)
  - Virginia (Box-folder 79/9)
  - Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 79/10)
  - Wyoming (Box-folder 79/11)
- Non-US Locations, 1908-1978; Series F
  - Afghanistan (Box-folder 79/12)
  - Antarctica (Box-folder 79/13)
  - The Arctic (Box-folder 79/14)
  - Austria (Box-folder 79/15)
  - Belgium (Box-folder 79/16)
  - Cambodia - Angkor Wat (Box-folder 79/17)
  - Cameroon (Box-folder 79/18)
  - Canada (1) (Box-folder 79/19)
  - Canada (2) (Box-folder 79/20)
  - Central America (Box-folder 79/21)
    Photographs labeled "Central America" on the back, but which do not specify the country.
  - China (Box-folder 79/22)
  - Cuba - Revolt, 1931-1933 (Box-folder 79/23)
  - Denmark (Box-folder 79/24)
  - Egypt - Tutankhamen's Tomb (Box-folder 80/1)
  - Ethipoia (Box-folder 80/2)
  - France (Box-folder 80/3)
    Includes a photograph of a replica of the Statue of Liberty located in Paris.
  - Germany (Box-folder 80/4)
  - Greece (Box-folder 80/5)
  - Himalayas (Box-folder 80/6)
  - Howland Island (Box-folder 80/7)
  - Israel (Box-folder 80/8)
  - Italy - Mt. Etna Eruption, 1928 (Box-folder 80/9)
  - Japan (Box-folder 80/10)
  - Japan - Hiroshima (Box-folder 80/11)
  - Mexico (Box-folder 80/12)
  - Philippines (Box-folder 80/13)
  - Russia (1) (Box-folder 80/14)
  - Russia (2) (Box-folder 80/15)
  - South Korea - Osan Boys' Town (Box-folder 80/16)
  - Turkey - Istanbul (Box-folder 80/17)
- Photoseries, circa 1880-1971; circa 1937-1971; Series G
  Photos that either ran together for a single special feature or as a recurring feature.
  - "America", 1970 February (Box-folder 81/1)
    Photographs used for an article discussing social upheaval and changing mores in the United States.
    One image moved to Oversize A due to size.
  - "Auto Drivers", 1970 August (Box-folder 81/2)
    Photographs which accompanied an article about lax vision requirements in licensing drivers.
  - Cigarette-Making, 1945 May (Box-folder 81/3)
    Photo series depicting Edgar Kennedy growing and curing tobacco, and then making a cigarette.
  - "Double Take", 1970-1971 (Box-folder 81/4)
    Photographs that make for an ironic image, such as a "For Sale" sign in a flooded field.
  - "Drunks", 1946 September (Box-folder 81/5)
    Series of photographs that ran in September 22 1946 issue, in which Dave O'Malley simulates cycle of public drunkeness.
  - "Farm Handy Ideas", 1950 (Box-folder 81/6)
    Photographs in which local farmers demonstrate homemade devices and other innovations.
  - "Five Generations", 1960-1963 (Box-folder 81/7)
    Portraits of families in which people from five generations of a family are present.
  - "High School Students", 1961 February (Box-folder 81/8)
    Photo series depicting Patricia Hatfield, Alden Jencks, Pamela Klein, Neil Nakadate, Bob Pederson, and Margo Tillson.
    One image of Margo Tillson moved to Oversize A - People due to size.
  - "Housemothers", 1958 March (Box-folder 81/9)
    Series of photographs relating to older women who oversee college women's groups.
  - "Housewife", 1968 (Box-folder 81/10)
    Series of photographs of Janet Toliver used to depict the average day and duties of a housewife.
  - Ooten Home, 1968 December (Box-folder 81/11)
    Photographs showcasing the Ooten Family's residence.
  - "Sins of America" (Box-folder 81/12)
    Reproductions of magazine illustrations from 1870-1900 which were considered racy or otherwise controversial in the late 19th century, compiled for a 1934 book by the title "Sins of America." The reproductions were published across several issues during the summer of 1934.
  - Surrealism, 1937 March (Box-folder 81/13)
    Warped-perspective photographs of Portland mayor Joseph Carson, Warren Erwin, Aaron Frank, Chester McCarty, Milton A. Miller, Tommy Luke, and Jimmy Richardson. Used in March 14, 1937 issue with article reporting on popularity of surrealist art.
  - Young Oregonians (1), 1935-1941 (Box-folder 81/14)
    Photographs (mostly cutouts) of children and teenagers used for a "Young Oregonians" collage.
    Prints in poor condition.
  - Young Oregonians (2) (Box-folder 81/15)
- Subjects, circa 1850-1983; circa 1910-1983; Series H
  - 4-H Club (Box-folder 81/16)
  - 8-Ball (Box-folder 81/17)
  - Abortion (Box-folder 81/18)
  - Abraham Lincoln Assassination (Box-folder 81/19)
  - Accidents (Box-folder 81/20)
  - Acheson Colloids Co. (Box-folder 81/21)
  - Acid (Box-folder 81/22)
  - Adobe Blocks (Box-folder 81/23)
  - Adoption (Box-folder 81/24)
  - Aerial Trams (Box-folder 81/25)
  - Aerifiers (Box-folder 81/26)
  - African-Americans (Box-folder 82/1)
    Includes photographs that had been originally filed under "Negro Housing."
  - Agates (Box-folder 82/2)
  - Agriculture, Subseries 1
    - Alfalfa (Box-folder 82/3)
    - Almonds (Box-folder 82/4)
    - Apples (Box-folder 82/5)
    - Appleseed Award (Box-folder 82/6)
    - Apricots (Box-folder 82/7)
    - Artichokes (Box-folder 82/8)
    - Asparagus (Box-folder 82/9)
    - Barley (Box-folder 82/10)
    - Beans (Box-folder 82/11)
    - Beekeeping (Box-folder 82/12)
    - Berry Harvesters (Box-folder 82/13)
      Mechanical berry picker.
    - Blackberries (Box-folder 82/14)
    - Blueberries (Box-folder 82/15)
    - Boysenberries (Box-folder 82/16)
    - Carrots (Box-folder 82/17)
    - Cascara Bark (Box-folder 82/18)
    - Cattle (1) (Box-folder 82/19)
      Includes images of cattle drives and cattle-branding.
    - Cattle (2) (Box-folder 82/20)
    - Cauliflower (Box-folder 82/21)
    - Cherries (Box-folder 82/22)
    - Clover Farm (Box-folder 82/23)
    - Corn (Box-folder 82/24)
    - Cotton (Box-folder 82/25)
    - Cranberries (Box-folder 82/26)
    - Crop Damage (Box-folder 82/27)
    - Crop Dusting (Box-folder 82/28)
      See also: Subjects - Pesticides.
    - Cucumbers (Box-folder 82/29)
    - Dairy Farms and Plants (Box-folder 82/30)
    - Dates (Box-folder 82/31)
    - Farm Equipment (Box-folder 82/32)
    - Farm Safety (Box-folder 83/1)
    - Farmers' Markets (Box-folder 83/2)
    - Farms (1) (Box-folder 83/3)
    - Farms (2) (Box-folder 83/4)
    - Farmworkers (Box-folder 83/5)
    - Field Burning (Box-folder 83/6)
    - Filberts (Box-folder 83/7)
    - Flax (Box-folder 83/8)
    - Flour and Flour Mills (Box-folder 83/9)
    - Fruit Drying (Box-folder 83/10)
    - Fruit Inspections (Box-folder 83/11)
    - Fur Farming (Box-folder 83/12)
    - Garlic (Box-folder 83/13)
    - Gooseberries (Box-folder 83/14)
    - Grain (Box-folder 83/15)
    - Grain Elevators (Box-folder 83/16)
    - Grapes (Box-folder 83/17)
    - Grass Seed (Box-folder 83/18)
    - Harvests (1) (Box-folder 83/19)
    - Harvests (2) (Box-folder 83/20)
    - Hay (Box-folder 83/21)
    - Hops (Box-folder 83/22)
    - Hotbeds (Box-folder 83/23)
    - Huckleberries (Box-folder 83/24)
    - Irrigation (Box-folder 83/25)
    - Lemons (Box-folder 84/1)
    - "Livestock Airlift", 1949 (Box-folder 84/2)
    - Maple Syrup (Box-folder 84/3)
    - Melons (Box-folder 84/4)
    - Mint (Box-folder 84/5)
    - Molasses Tank Farms (Box-folder 84/6)
    - Mushroom Farms (Box-folder 84/7)
    - Oranges (Box-folder 84/8)
    - Paw Paw Fruit (Box-folder 84/9)
    - Pears (Box-folder 84/10)
    - Peppermint (Box-folder 84/11)
    - Persimmons (Box-folder 84/12)
    - Poultry (Box-folder 84/13)
    - Raspberries (Box-folder 84/14)
    - Seeding (Box-folder 84/15)
    - Sheep Breeders (Box-folder 84/16)
    - Squash (Box-folder 84/17)
    - Sugar Beets (Box-folder 84/18)
    - Sweet Peas (Box-folder 84/19)
    - Walnuts (Box-folder 84/20)
    - Wheat Sales Chart, 1971 April (Box-folder 84/21)
      Graph comparing amount of wheat sold by the United States, Canada and Australia from 1966 to 1970.
  - Agricultural Stabilization (Box-folder 84/22)
  - Air Raid Sirens (Box-folder 84/23)
  - Allis-Chalmers Corp. (Box-folder 84/24)
  - Almanacs (Box-folder 84/25)
  - Alphabets (Box-folder 84/26)
  - Altars (Box-folder 84/27)
  - Aluminum (Box-folder 84/28)
  - Amber (Box-folder 84/29)
  - American Federation of Government Employees (Box-folder 84/30)
  - American Legion (Box-folder 84/31)
  - American Medical Association (Box-folder 84/32)
  - American Mother Award (Box-folder 84/33)
  - American Municipal Association (Box-folder 84/34)
  - American Newspaper Publishers Association (Box-folder 84/35)
  - American Telephone & Telegraph Co. (AT&T) (Box-folder 84/36)
  - American Youth Congress (Box-folder 84/37)
  - Americans Living Abroad (Box-folder 84/38)
  - Amish People (Box-folder 84/39)
  - Ammunition (Box-folder 84/40)
  - Animal Control (Box-folder 85/1)
  - Animal Shelters (Box-folder 85/2)
  - Antennas (Box-folder 85/3)
  - Antlers (Box-folder 85/4)
  - Anti-Pollution Cartoon, 1927 (Box-folder 85/5)
    Cartoon by Grants Pass resident Florence Gibson McCabe, which won the "Outdoor Good Manners" contest held by the American Nature Association. Includes a photograph of McCabe.
  - Antiques (Box-folder 85/6)
  - Archaeology (Box-folder 85/7)
  - Architecture (Box-folder 85/8)
  - Architectural Awards (Box-folder 85/9)
    Photographs of buildings whose architects won award for the building.
  - Arson (Box-folder 85/10)
  - Art, Subseries 2
    - Art Education (Box-folder 85/11)
    - Art Fairs (Box-folder 85/12)
    - Arts and Crafts (1) (Box-folder 85/13)
    - Arts and Crafts (2) (Box-folder 85/14)
    - Calligraphy (Box-folder 85/15)
    - Carvings (Box-folder 85/16)
    - "Children of the World Paint the Old Testament" Contest, 1978 December (Box-folder 85/17)
      Photographs of drawings made by pupils at Portland schools Hillel Academy and St. Thomas Moore Catholic School for the contest.
    - "Cross-Town Bus", 1968 January (Box-folder 85/18)
      Images from an anthology of art by David Douglas High School students.
    - Driftwood Carvings and Sculptures (Box-folder 85/19)
    - Etchings (Box-folder 85/20)
    - Exhibits (1) (Box-folder 85/21)
    - Exhibits (2) (Box-folder 85/22)
    - Exhibits (3) (Box-folder 85/23)
    - Glassworks (Box-folder 86/1)
      Includes stained glass windows.
    - Leather-Tooling (Box-folder 86/2)
    - "Lena the Hyena" Contest, 1946 (Box-folder 86/3)
    - Mosaics (Box-folder 86/4)
    - Murals (1) (Box-folder 86/5)
    - Murals (2) (Box-folder 86/6)
    - Oriental Art (Box-folder 86/7)
    - Paintings and Drawings (1) (Box-folder 86/8)
    - Paintings and Drawings (2) (Box-folder 86/9)
    - Scholastic Art (Box-folder 86/10)
      Includes photographs of scholastic art contest winners.
    - Sculpture (1) (Box-folder 86/11)
    - Sculpture (2) (Box-folder 86/12)
    - Sculpture (3) (Box-folder 86/13)
    - Sculpture (4) (Box-folder 87/1)
    - Other Art Forms (Box-folder 87/2)
  - Artesian Wells (Box-folder 87/3)
  - Asian-American People (Box-folder 87/4)
  - Assaults (Box-folder 87/5)
  - Astronauts (Box-folder 87/6)
  - Atomic Blasts (Box-folder 87/7)
  - Atomic Research (Box-folder 87/8)
  - Attics (Box-folder 87/9)
  - Auctions (Box-folder 87/10)
  - Audio Amplifiers (Box-folder 87/11)
  - Australian People (Box-folder 87/12)
  - Autistic Children (Box-folder 87/13)
  - Avalanches (Box-folder 87/14)
  - Aviation, Subseries 3
    - Air Ambulances and Mercy Flights (Box-folder 87/15)
    - Air Beacons (Box-folder 87/16)
    - Air Cargo and Air Mail (Box-folder 87/17)
    - Air Shows (Box-folder 87/18)
    - Air Tours (Box-folder 87/19)
    - Air Traffic Control Towers (Box-folder 87/20)
    - Airplane Accidents - General (1) (Box-folder 87/21)
    - Airplane Accidents - General (2) (Box-folder 87/22)
    - Airplane Accidents - General (3) (Box-folder 88/1)
    - Airplane Accidents - General (4) (Box-folder 88/2)
    - Airplane Accidents - General (5) (Box-folder 88/3)
    - Airplane Accidents - Canary Islands Crash, 1977 March (Box-folder 88/4)
      Also called the Tenerife Airport Disaster, the crash was the deadliest accidental plane crash in history, killing 583 people.
      Also includes an April 1977 photograph of a mass funeral in California for more than 100 victims.
    - Airplane Accidents - Eastern Airlines Crash, 1975 June (Box-folder 88/5)
    - Airplane Accidents - Empire State Building Crash, 1945 July (Box-folder 88/6)
    - Airplane Accidents - Kenner, Louisiana Crash, 1982 July (Box-folder 88/7)
    - Airplane Accidents - Oien Family, 1967 October (Box-folder 88/8)
    - Airplane Accidents - San Diego Collision, 1978 September (Box-folder 88/9)
    - Airplane Accidents - Snell Crash, 1947 October (Box-folder 88/10)
      Crash near Oregon California border that killed Oregon governor Earl Snell, secretary of state Robert S. Farrell, and state senate president Marshall Cornett.
    - Airplane Accidents - United Airlines Crash in Portland, 1978 December (Box-folder 88/11)
    - Airplane Accidents - Washington, D.C. Crash, 1982 January (Box-folder 88/12)
      Photographs relate to plane crash into 14th Street Bridge across the Potomac River in January 1981.
      Includes March 1981 photograph of one of the survivors.
    - Airplane Accidents - Will Rogers and Wiley Post, 1935 August (Box-folder 88/13)
    - Airplane Hangars (Box-folder 88/14)
    - Airplane Hijackings (Box-folder 88/15)
    - Airplane Kits (Box-folder 88/16)
    - Airplane Maitenance Stands (Box-folder 88/17)
    - Airplanes - General (1) (Box-folder 88/18)
    - Airplanes - General (2) (Box-folder 88/19)
    - Airplanes - General (3) (Box-folder 88/20)
    - Airplanes - General (4) (Box-folder 89/1)
    - Airplanes - General (5) (Box-folder 89/2)
    - Airplanes - General (6) (Box-folder 89/3)
    - Airplanes - Breese Aircraft, 1930 April (Box-folder 89/4)
      Airplane built in Beaverton.
    - Airplanes - "City of Portland" (Box-folder 89/5)
    - Airport Security (Box-folder 89/6)
    - Aviation Equipment (Box-folder 89/7)
    - Blimp Accidents - Shenandoah, 1925 (Box-folder 89/8)
    - Blimps (Box-folder 89/9)
    - Commercial Airlines (Box-folder 89/10)
    - Cristofferson-Graham Flight to the Arctic, 1932 (Box-folder 89/11)
      Photographs related to airplane journey undertaken by Portlander Edna E. Cristofferson and Alaskan William R. Graham
    - Early Aviators (Box-folder 89/12)
      See also: Aviation - Pilots
    - Endurance Flights (Box-folder 89/13)
      See also: Aviation - Rankin Endurance Flights
    - Experimental Aircraft (Box-folder 89/14)
    - Flight Attendants (Box-folder 89/15)
    - Flight Paths (Box-folder 89/16)
    - Gliders (Box-folder 89/17)
      Includes hang gliders.
    - Helicopters (Box-folder 89/18)
    - Hot Air Balloons (Box-folder 89/19)
    - Pilots (Box-folder 89/20)
      See also: Aviation - Early Aviators; People series under pilot's surname.
    - Rankin Endurance Flights, 1930; 1932 (Box-folder 90/1)
      Undertaken by Tex Rankin and his brothers.
      See also: Aviation - Endurance Flights
    - Russian Transpolar Flight (Box-folder 90/2)
      1937 flight that landed in Vancouver, Washington.
      Most photographs relate to commemoration of event held in 1975.
    - Seaplanes (Box-folder 90/3)
    - Trans-Pacific Flight Attempt, 1925 August (Box-folder 90/4)
    - Wright Brothers Airplanes (Box-folder 90/5)
  - Awards (Box-folder 90/6)
  - Babies (1) (Box-folder 90/7)
  - Babies (2) (Box-folder 90/8)
  - Bachelor Balls (Box-folder 90/9)
  - Bacteria (Box-folder 90/10)
  - Balloons (Box-folder 90/11)
  - Bank Robberies (1) (Box-folder 90/12)
    Includes robberies of Portland banks.
  - Bank Robberies (2) (Box-folder 90/13)
  - Bank Robberies (3) (Box-folder 90/14)
  - Bank Robberies (4) (Box-folder 90/15)
  - Baptisms (Box-folder 90/16)
  - Bar Mitzvahs (Box-folder 90/17)
  - Barbecue Pits (Box-folder 90/18)
  - Barbershops (Box-folder 90/19)
  - Barns (Box-folder 90/20)
  - Bathrooms (Box-folder 90/21)
  - Bathtubs (Box-folder 90/22)
  - Batons (Box-folder 91/1)
  - Bayonets (Box-folder 91/2)
  - Bazaars (Box-folder 91/3)
    Includes photographs related to church-sponsored craft fairs.
  - Beauty Salons (Box-folder 91/4)
  - Bed and Breakfasts (Box-folder 91/5)
  - Beds and Bedrooms (Box-folder 91/6)
  - Beeswax (Box-folder 91/7)
  - Benches (Box-folder 91/8)
  - Bicycle Shelters (Box-folder 91/9)
  - Bicycles (Box-folder 91/10)
    See also: Sports and Recreation - Bicycling
  - Billboards (Box-folder 91/11)
  - Bird Feeders (Box-folder 91/12)
  - Birdhouses (Box-folder 91/13)
  - Birth Registration Cards (Box-folder 91/14)
  - Birthday Celebrations (Box-folder 91/15)
  - Black History Week (Box-folder 91/16)
  - Blackouts (Box-folder 91/17)
    Contains images related to both blackouts undertaken for safety during World War II and in the 1970s for energy conservation.
  - Blacksmiths (Box-folder 91/18)
  - Blind People (1) (Box-folder 91/19)
  - Blind People (2) (Box-folder 91/20)
  - Block Home Program (Box-folder 91/21)
  - Boats and Other Watercraft, Subseries 4
    See also: Military - Navy.
    - General (1) (Box-folder 91/22)
    - General (2) (Box-folder 91/23)
    - Anchors (Box-folder 91/24)
    - Barges (Box-folder 91/25)
    - Boat and Ship Building (Box-folder 91/26)
    - Boat Prices, 1957 February (Box-folder 91/27)
      Series of photographs showing different small boats, which ran in February 24 1957 issue with captions detailing the approximate cost of each type.
    - Boat Safety (Box-folder 91/28)
    - Boat Shows (Box-folder 92/1)
    - Boat Trips (Box-folder 92/2)
    - Buoys (Box-folder 92/3)
    - Boathouses (Box-folder 92/4)
    - Canoes (Box-folder 92/5)
    - Christmas Ship (Box-folder 92/6)
    - Columbia River Pilots (Box-folder 92/7)
    - Dredges (Box-folder 92/8)
    - Ferries (1) (Box-folder 92/9)
    - Ferries (2) (Box-folder 92/10)
    - Fire Boats (Box-folder 92/11)
      Includes a May 1926 photograph of a fireboat at the inauguration of the Burnside Bridge.
    - Fishing Boats (Box-folder 92/12)
      See also: Subjects - Fishing.
    - Gambling Ships (Box-folder 92/13)
    - Houseboats (Box-folder 92/14)
    - Ice Breakers (Box-folder 92/15)
    - Kayaks (Box-folder 92/16)
    - Landing Craft (Box-folder 92/17)
    - Lifeboats and Life Rafts (Box-folder 92/18)
    - Sailboats (Box-folder 93/1)
    - Scrapped Battleships (Box-folder 93/2)
    - Ship Figureheads (Box-folder 93/3)
    - Ship Launchings (1) (Box-folder 93/4)
      Mostly photographs of ship launchings during World War II in Portland. Includes photographs of people involved with ship launching ceremonies.
    - Ship Launchings (2) (Box-folder 93/5)
    - Ship Launchings (3) (Box-folder 93/6)
    - Ship Launchings (4) (Box-folder 93/7)
    - Shipwrecks and Other Boat Accidents (Box-folder 93/8)
    - Steamboats (Box-folder 93/9)
  - Boeing Corp. (Box-folder 93/10)
  - Boilers (Box-folder 93/11)
  - Boise-Cascade Co. (Box-folder 93/12)
    See also: Portland - Boise-Cascade Building.
  - Bombs and Bombings (Box-folder 93/13)
  - Bones (Box-folder 93/14)
  - Bonneville Power Administration (Box-folder 93/15)
    Contains images of Bonneville Power Administration sites in both Oregon and Washington.
  - Book Fairs (Box-folder 94/1)
  - Books (1) (Box-folder 94/2)
  - Books (2) (Box-folder 94/3)
  - Bookstores (Box-folder 94/4)
  - Boots (Box-folder 94/5)
  - Bottle Messages (Box-folder 94/6)
  - Bottles (Box-folder 94/7)
  - Boxcar Homes (Box-folder 94/8)
  - Boxes (Box-folder 94/9)
  - Boy Scouts (Box-folder 94/10)
  - Boys Nation (Box-folder 94/11)